# **GARRARD KITCHEN, B.Sc (Hons)**

+44 (0)1704 233 521 +44 (0)7795 575 000 garrardkitchen@gmail.com www.garrardkitchen.com skype: garrard.kitchen

1 Beresford Drive Churchtown Southport PR9 7JY

## Interests include:

- Serverless technology
- DevOps
- AWS
- Azure
- Machine Learning
- Security
- Research
- Project Management
- Product Owner

## Ideal locations:

- Southport
- Liverpool
- Manchester
- Preston

Full driving license

## **Profile**

I am a technical project leader, experienced in communicating at all levels, with commercial awareness, I am accustomed to identifying improvement opportunities outside of scope.

At my last position, CTO/Developer, I had developed and nurtured a culture of DevOps. This gave me and my team the freedom, responsibility and ownership necessary to help drive the business. With the application of appropriate tools (CloudWatch, Datadog, OpsGenie, Sentry.io, Epsagon, Stackify, Slack) and frameworks, I instilled the AWS Operational Excellence & Reliability pillars into the company's culture. This included, but was not limited too, the creation of runbooks across multiple platforms to automate (e.g. autoscale ECS Fargate containers) and monitor both infrastructure and solution features to minimise downtime (RPO). I architected massively scalable HA & secure solutions with DR, with these solutions driven by serverless technology (such as AWS Lambda, Step Functions, API Gateway & ECS Fargate) and loosely coupled systems that are fault-tolerant by design (e.g. Amazon SQS, SNS & Kinesis Data Streams). I used .NET Core (C# & F#), python and node.js interchangeably during my time in this position. My architecture included several different types of database (RDBMS, NoSQL & in-memory) including Aurora, MS SQL, DynamoDB, ElasticSearch & Redis). All my systems were integrated, packaged and deployed using a common CI/CD approach using tools such as Azure DevOps, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, OctopusDeploy, BitBucket Pipelines and Jenkins. My chosen container orchestration solution was ECS Fargate with ECR and Docker Hub registries. All stages of the release cycle monitored, maintained and informed. I created a polyglot development environment with a team that gave maximum effort and commitment. My serverless journey started on the Azure platform several years ago. I have used Azure for several years and using this platform I have architected, developed and deployed several massively scalable solutions.

I have a proven track record of systems integrations, acting as a remote worker manager of a European team, project managing across multiple time zones and cultures. I have a strong technical background in both server & client side development as well as serverless technologies (infrastructure, services & frameworks) and solutions delivery driven by DevOps. I am obsessive about quality UX, and with solutions that deliver on a positive CX. I am a full-stack developer.

## **Experience**

CTO, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Sep 2008—Present
I managed a team of remote workers around Europe to develop single server,
HA & cloud based solutions using a range of technologies.

I lead technical projects, architecting product systems and feature solutions and coordinating integrations with partner/SI teams around the globe.

The role is varied; ranging from technical presentations to CxO, DevOps, Full-Stack development to root cause analysis. I categorise myself as a CTO/ developer with extensive serverless development experience specialising in DevOps. Reporting directly to the CEO.

Contractor, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Jan 2007—Sep 2008

I was employed originally to develop an API for a company's client/server product. This involved employing Unit testing techniques such as TDD and documentation software and then to ship to integration partners.

I was also awarded the project to design and develop an e-learning and coaching web platform, hosted on self-managed Rackspace servers.

The work gave me my first experience of AWS services.

I worked with partners & system integrators around the world. I was asked to work full-time.

Contractor, Co-Op; Bromsgrove — 2005—Jan 2006

I was commissioned to support and enhance solutions using ASP, ASP.NET, c#, javascript, HTML and CSS. This role also included supporting Cadbury's with the Holos product (EIS). I was asked to work full-time.

Client-side web developer Team Lead, AIM Technology — Apr 2003—2004

I headed up the client-side development effort of a Scorecard web-application.

This was eventually bought by Aspect.

Data Architect, AIM Technology — Nov 2002—Aug 2003

My primary role was to consolidate data from disparate systems into a

Scorecard application. My responsibilities included providing an OLAP solution,
BI, data analytics, pre-sales support, product installation, support and
diagnostics. I worked both onsite and offsite. Other duties included enhancing
the corporate website.

## Education

John Moores University, Liverpool — Business Information Systems Degree (Hons), 1994

North East Wales Institute, Connah's Quay - National Diploma in Computer Science, 1990

# Certification

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate Certification, 2018-2021 AWS Developer - Associate Certification, 2017-2020

1st Dan, Black belt, 2010

## **Skills**

Technical project leadership, remote team management, technical presentations and documentation, experienced in communication at all levels, meeting facilitator, educator, coach, agile development, root cause analysis and problem solving, microservices, AWS certified, Azure, full-stack developer, serverless development, CI/CD, system integration, RDBMS, NoSQL, ElasticSearch, Big Data, containers (ECS Fargate, Linux, Windows), CloudFormation (configuration as code), git, C#, F#, javascript, ES6, .NET Core, .NET Framework, <u>ASP.NET</u> Core Razor Pages, RESTful APIs, Sockets, Python, Node.js, Go, ETL, Microsoft, Linux, Authentication, UX, Bootstrap, JQuery, Angular, React, Vue

## References

Costas Johnson - CEO Qualtrak Solutions, +44 (0)777 5520 459, <a href="mailto:costas.johnson@qualtrak.com">costas.johnson@qualtrak.com</a> - <a href="mailto:http://www.garrardkitchen.com/reference.pdf">http://www.garrardkitchen.com/reference.pdf</a>

## **Hobbies**

Cycling, reading, research, cooking, walking, drone flying, golf and Ju-Jitsu